Only Human: HIV-negative Gay Men in the AIDS Epidemic Archive 1995-1996 MSS 376
Fales Library and Special Collections
Only Human: HIV-negative Gay Men in the AIDS Epidemic Archive
1995-1996
MSS 376
Fales Library and Special Collections
2.0 linear feet
Only Human: HIV-negative Gay Men in the AIDS Epidemic Archive is comprised of source material, work-in-progress sample reels, masters, and the final cut of the film "Only Human: HIV-negative Gay Men in the AIDS Epidemic. "Only Human: HIV-Negative Gay Men in the AIDS Epidemic" is a documentary that explores the relationship between HIV risk reduction practices and the advent of AIDS.
Deitcher, David
DiFeliciantonio, Tina
Mookas, Ioannis
Nitty Gritty Productions.
Biographical/Historical note
"Only Human: HIV-Negative Gay Men in the AIDS Epidemic" is a documentary that explores the relationship between HIV risk reduction practices and the advent of AIDS. The documentary includes interviews that draw from the sexual experiences of HIV-negative men from a variety of backgrounds. "Only Human" simultaneously follows the dramatic struggle of one gay Latino youth's to balance health with sexuality.
Sources:
Turner Classic Movies
Internet Movie Database
Scope and Content
Only Human: HIV-negative Gay Men in the AIDS Epidemic Archive is comprised of source material, work-in-progress sample reels, masters, and the final cut of the film "Only Human: HIV-negative Gay Men in the AIDS Epidemic." The film was directed by Ioannis Mookas, written by David Deitcher, and co-produced by Mookas, Deitcher, and Tina DiFeliciantonio. The videorecordings span from 1995 to 1998.
The collection is arranged in one series:
Series I: Videorecordings: contains 2 boxes of VHS and Betacam SP.
Arrangement
Videorecordings are arranged chronologically, when recordings are dated.
Related Material at Fales Library and Special Collections
Mix Collection
Nelson Sullivan Video Collection
Gay Cable Network Archive
Provenance
The Only Human: HIV-negative Gay Men in the AIDS Epidemic Archive was donated to Fales Library by David Deitcher, in September 2013.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
Blythe, Bernard; Cordero, Carlos; Diaz, Henry; Fung, Alvin; MAPP, Derrick; Marer, Marcelo; Miller, Reggie; Montoya-Montez, Andy; Sayed, Javid; Sims, Neil; AIDS (Disease) and art |z United States.; AIDS (Disease) |x Social aspects |z New York (State) |z New York.; Film.; Gay men |z United States.; Gays |x Political activity |z New York (State) |z New York.; Video recordings |x Political aspects.; Video recordings |x Social aspects.; Videotapes |x Preservation.
- Series I: Videorecordings
  General note
  Audio levels modulate on some of these videos.
  - Only Human: Reel #1, Neil Sims, December 16, 1995 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0001)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    TRT: 00:30:00
    Original Format: VHS
    Conditions Governing Access
    Access DVD available by appointment only.
  - Only Human: Reel #2, Neil Sims, December 16, 1995 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0002)
  - Only Human: Reel #3, Neil Sims, December 16, 1995 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0003)
  - Only Human: Reel #4, Neil Sims, December 16, 1995 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0004)
  - Only Human: Reel #5, Carlos Cordero, December 16, 1995 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0005)
    TRT: 00:30:00 Original Format: VHS
  - Only Human: Reel #6, Carlos Cordero, December 16, 1995 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0006)
  - Only Human: Reel #7, Carlos Cordero, December 16, 1995 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0007)
  - Only Human: Reel #8, Carlos Cordero, December 16, 1995 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0008)
  - Reel #9, Henry Diaz (Master), December 16, 1995 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0009)
    TRT: unknown
    Format: Betacam SP
    Currently unavailable.
  - Only Human: Reel #9, Henry Diaz, December 16, 1995 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0010)
  - Reel #10, Henry Diaz (Master), December 16, 1995 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0011)
  - Only Human: Reel #10, Henry Diaz, December 16, 1995 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0012)
  - Reel #11, Henry Diaz (Master), December 16, 1995 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0013)
  - Only Human: Reel #11, Henry Diaz, December 16, 1995 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0014)
  - Reel #12, Henry Diaz (Master), December 16, 1995 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0015)
  - Only Human: Reel #12, Henry Diaz, [ca. 1995] (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0016)
  - Only Human: Reel #13, Andy Montoya-Montez, [ca. 1995] (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0017)
    TRT:00:30:00
  - Only Human: Reel #14, Andy Montoya-Montez, [ca. 1995] (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0018)
  - Only Human: Reel #15, Andy Montoya-Montez, [ca. 1995] (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0019)
  - Gay Pride: Reel #20, Derrick MAPP, June 30, 1996 and July 1, 1996 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0020)
  - Reel #21, Derrick MAPP, July 1, 1996 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0021)
  - Reel #22, Derrick MAPP, July 1, 1996 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0022)
  - Reel #23, Derrick MAPP, July 1, 1996 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0023)
  - Reel #24, Derrick MAPP, July 1, 1996 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0024)
  - Reel #25: [1]--Derrick MAPP (Portrait) [2]--Javid Sayed, July 1, 1996 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0025)
  - Reel #26: Javid Sayed, July 1, 1996 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0026)
  - Reel #27: Javid Sayed, July 1, 1996 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0027)
  - Reel #28: Javid Sayed, July 1, 1996 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0028)
  - Reel #29: [1]--Javid Sayed [2]--Bernnard Blythe, July 2, 1996 (Box 1, Media ID: 376.0029)
  - Reel #30: Bernnard Blythe, July 2, 1996 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0030)
    TRT: 00:29:52
  - Reel #31: Bernnard Blythe, July 2, 1996 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0031)
    TRT: 00:31:46
  - Reel #32: Bernard Blythe, July 2, 1996 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0032)
    TRT: 00:31:11
  - Reel #33: [1]--Bernard Blythe [2]--Reggie Miller, July 2, 1996 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0033)
    TRT: 00:31:02
    Format: VHS
  - Reel #34: Reggie Miller, July 2, 1996 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0034)
    TRT: 00:29:04
  - Reel #35: Reggie Miller, July 2, 1996 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0035)
    TRT: 00:31:06
  - Reel #36: [1]--Reginald Miller [2]--Marcelo Marer, July 2, 1996-July 3, 1996 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0036)
    TRT: 00:31:33 Original Format: VHS
  - Reel #37: Marcelo Marer, July 3, 1996 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0037)
    TRT: 00:32:42
  - Reel #38: Marcelo Marer, July 3, 1996 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0038)
    TRT: 00:31:26
  - Reel #39: Marcelo Marer, July 3, 1996 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0039)
    TRT: 00:28:17
  - Reel #40: Alvin Fung, July 3, 1996 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0040)
    TRT: 00:30:07
  - Reel #41: Alvin Fung, July 3, 1996 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0041)
    TRT: 00:30:15
  - "Only Human" Sample Video (Master), March 2, 1996 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0042)
  - Only Human: Work in Progress Reel (Protection Master), September 1, 1996 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0043)
  - Only Human: HIV-negative gay men in the AIDS epidemic work-in-progress sample reel, undated (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0044)
    TRT: 00:10:41
    Original Format: 3/4" Umatic
  - Only Human: HIV-negative gay men in the AIDS epidemic work-in-progress sample reel, undated (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0045)
    TRT: 00:12:22
  - Only Human: HIV-negative gay men in the AIDS epidemic (complete), 1998 (Box 2, Media ID: 376.0046)
    TRT: 00:58:16